JANET YODER

7205 W. 21st. Street Greeley, CO 80634 kajcyoder@comcast.net

www.linkedin.com/in/janetyoder Cell: 970-396-9428

SUMMARY

Accomplished professional that is combining a strong software development background with fresh Web development skills. Top strengths include: excellent interpersonal skills, utilizing teamwork to get results, and being detail-oriented without losing sight of the overall goal. Experience in:

- Designing, building, editing web sites
- Responsive design
- Knowledgeable in Adobe Suite
- Product/Project/Program Management
- Scrum Master and Agile practices
- Escalation Management and process creation

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Visual Studio, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML/HTML5, CSS3, C++, C#, COM, MFC, XML
- Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Microsoft Project, PowerPoint, Word, Excel, Visio, SharePoint
- Subversion, GitHub, Brackets, HP Quality Center/ALM, XPlanner, VMWare, InstallShield

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Front Range Community College Longmont, CO

WebLab - A Web Development Boot Camp, FRCC Certificate (2014)

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, UI/UX Design

Aims Community College Greeley, CO

Graphics Software and Applications Certificate (2014)

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign CS5 and CS6, Typography and Layout, Electronic Pre-press

Complete Web Authoring Class (2014)

HTML5 and CSS3 – Created a 5 page website for the final project.

University of Northern Colorado Greeley, CO

Bachelor of Arts, Mathematics, Emphasis: Computer Science

Corporate Sponsored and Personal Training

- Codecademy.com Completed JavaScript, JQuery, PHP class.
- Currently learning WordPress on my own.
- Writing Windows 8 Metro Applications with XAML, Windows Store Data binding and MVVM
- Agile Estimating and Planning, Coaching Agile Teams, Demonstrating Responsibility: The Mindset of an Agile Leader, Designing the Agile, Organization Who Does What, Certified Scrum Master Training, Windows CE Development, Microsoft SharePoint 2010
- Project Management, Program Management, Project Leadership and Communication, TCP/IP Workshop, Managing Offshore Vendors
- Java, Fundamentals of XML, Programming with C#, Power ASP .NET Programming
- Prototyped with C# on writing Window 8 applications for the Windows Store. Owner of the submission of my team's HP Scan and Capture application to the Windows Store.

Janet Yoder Page 2

KEY PROJECTS AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

To view the websites and source code go to: http://jcyoder.github.io/

The Kitchen Web Site

This five page site uses HTML5 and CSS3 to demonstrate the use of HTML forms, a Google form, an embedded Google map, AJAX calls, tables, iframes, @media for responsive design and some jQuery.

Todos Web Application

Todos demonstrates the use of HTML5, CSS3, and jQuery to allow users to add, remove, edit, cross off, and filter todo list items.

Calculator

This tool uses HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript event handlers to create a basic calculator.

Colorado Travel

Main page example showing the use of jQuery event handlers for menu/submenu navigation and the use of responsive design.

Adobe Suite Projects

- InDesign 2015 calendar, magazine layout, 8 page booklet
- Illustrator Building created with perspective tool, coffee mug drawn with pen and gradient mesh tools, playing card deck design, personal portrait
- Photoshop Food Magazine cover, photo collage, posters

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ALLPROWEBTOOLS, Fort Collins, CO

August 2014-Present

Web Development Intern

Creating email advertisements, coupons, and other graphic design content for clients. Gaining experience in HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap 3, PHP, and MySQL.

HEWLETT-PACKARD, Greeley/Fort Collins, CO 1993-2013

Sustained Engineering Lead for Windows Software (2013)

Led the team to create processes for managing customer issues and pre-sales opportunities for a \$182 million scanner software portfolio.

Scanner and Camera Product Engineer and Program Manager (1997-2013)

Managed the requirements, schedule and software solution life-cycle for HP's market leading scanners and HP Photosmart cameras.

Certified Scrum Master (2009-2012)

Led the team transition from a waterfall product life-cycle to using Agile. Managed the Scrum process to ensure the Scrum values, practices and rules were enacted and enforced.

Software Developer (1993-2003)

Developed code and maintained components shipped with HP Scanjet Scanner solutions, HP Photosmart Digital Cameras, HP Personal and Photo Printers and HP All-in-One devices.